<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Josh Matz</title>
    <link>http://joshmatz.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Josh Matz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://joshmatz.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Your content can wait</title>
      <link>http://joshmatz.com/post/your-content-can-wait/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshmatz.com/post/your-content-can-wait/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good content doesn’t need to be published immediately.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a week ago I re-discovered Buffer, an app that lets users easily schedule their social media content to be published at a later date. I didn’t think much of it until I started using it consistently. A week in and I’m now a paying user. Not only that, it’s made me wonder how we can apply Buffer’s principles to any content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scheduling content isn’t new but for a variety of reasons I’ve not found it easy to exhibit patience over my writing. Inspiration would hit then I’d write and publish; I’d finish reading an article then summarize and share. That impatience lead to irregular and odd times for my content to be published. It didn’t just equate to missed eyeballs and low engagement, it also meant I didn’t have a schedule to keep me on track and accountable to my goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a world of instants. Instant video. Instant messaging. Instant oatmeal. It’s tough to take a step back and not publish your content instantly. When I started using Buffer it disconnected me from that instant publication. I realized it’s not the timeliness of your content that matters if you aren’t publishing any at all. And if your content is good then it can wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: I wrote this 3 years ago. I no longer pay for Buffer as I’m not sharing as much content as I used to, but I still love and use it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://joshmatz.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 14:02:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshmatz.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! I’m Josh Matz and I’m currently living in Austin, Texas with my wife, Rachael Matz, and dog Kindle. (There’s also a cat, Tonks, but I let Rachael take ownership of him.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a self taught web developer and received a BFA in Graphic Design at Baylor University. I’m currently working at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.invisionapp.com&#34;&gt;InVision&lt;/a&gt; where I help make the world&amp;rsquo;s leading prototyping, collaboration &amp;amp; workflow platform. Previous employers include &lt;a href=&#34;https://srcclr.com&#34;&gt;SourceClear&lt;/a&gt; (a security startup) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springbox.com&#34;&gt;Springbox&lt;/a&gt; (a digital agency).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like my work, feel free to get in touch or catch me on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/joshmatz&#34;&gt;@joshmatz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern European Art Timeline</title>
      <link>http://joshmatz.com/mea_timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 14:02:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshmatz.com/mea_timeline/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hi there! If you found this page, my guess it&amp;rsquo;s not what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for! Sorry about that. Feel free to skip the story below and go straight to the real &lt;a href=&#34;http://jmhosting.space/mea_timeline&#34;&gt;modern European art timeline&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, here&amp;rsquo;s some background on the timeline you&amp;rsquo;re using!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-timeline:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;The Timeline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the Spring semester of 2012, a Modern European Art class was being conducted. Nearer to the end of the semester our professor lamented that there was no good website available to give students an overview of the timeline she was teaching. So she came up with an idea: have her current students create an asset that could be useful for years to come. She was able to convince around 8 of us to take on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks the 8 of us divided and conquered. One of us developed the site and data entry tools. A couple others designed it. A few more researched and entered information. We all brought it together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the timeline was launched, just over 4 years ago, it&amp;rsquo;s seen growth our class would never have imagined. It&amp;rsquo;s now receiving over 100,000 pageviews a year from roughly 25,000 unique visitors. It&amp;rsquo;s staggering to see how many people are receiving value out of a project we did for one college class. Thank you so much for visiting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason you&amp;rsquo;re seeing this is I&amp;rsquo;ve had to move the site from where it once lived. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, it&amp;rsquo;s still alive and kicking, it just has a new URL at &lt;a href=&#34;http://jmhosting.space/mea_timeline&#34;&gt;jmhosting.space/mea_timeline&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re glad you enjoy the site, please let me know if you have any questions or comments about it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>