<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mea_timelines on Josh Matz</title>
    <link>/mea_timeline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mea_timelines on Josh Matz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 14:02:37 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/mea_timeline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern European Art Timeline</title>
      <link>/mea_timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 14:02:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mea_timeline/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hi there! If you found this page, my guess it&amp;rsquo;s not what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for! Sorry about that. Feel free to skip the story below and go straight to the real &lt;a href=&#34;http://jmhosting.space/mea_timeline&#34;&gt;modern European art timeline&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, here&amp;rsquo;s some background on the timeline you&amp;rsquo;re using!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-timeline:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;The Timeline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the Spring semester of 2012, a Modern European Art class was being conducted. Nearer to the end of the semester our professor lamented that there was no good website available to give students an overview of the timeline she was teaching. So she came up with an idea: have her current students create an asset that could be useful for years to come. She was able to convince around 8 of us to take on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks the 8 of us divided and conquered. One of us developed the site and data entry tools. A couple others designed it. A few more researched and entered information. We all brought it together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the timeline was launched, just over 4 years ago, it&amp;rsquo;s seen growth our class would never have imagined. It&amp;rsquo;s now receiving over 100,000 pageviews a year from roughly 25,000 unique visitors. It&amp;rsquo;s staggering to see how many people are receiving value out of a project we did for one college class. Thank you so much for visiting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason you&amp;rsquo;re seeing this is I&amp;rsquo;ve had to move the site from where it once lived. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, it&amp;rsquo;s still alive and kicking, it just has a new URL at &lt;a href=&#34;http://jmhosting.space/mea_timeline&#34;&gt;jmhosting.space/mea_timeline&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re glad you enjoy the site, please let me know if you have any questions or comments about it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>